<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Act, for a publick fast. Edinburgh, the thirteenth day of June, 1690 years.</title>
            <author>Scotland. Parliament. Committee of Estates.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B05182</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S1085</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R183890</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">53981709</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 53981709</idno>
            <idno type="VID">180331</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B05182)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 180331)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2826:19)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Act, for a publick fast. Edinburgh, the thirteenth day of June, 1690 years.</title>
                  <author>Scotland. Parliament. Committee of Estates.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by the heir of Andrew Anderson, Printer to the King and Queens most excellent Majesties,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno Dom. 1690.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Initial letter.</note>
                  <note>Signed at end: Extracted forth of the records of Parliament, by me Th. Burnet, Cls. Reg.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Public worship --  Scotland --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Fasts and feasts --  Church of Scotland --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Scotland --  History --  1689-1702 --  Sources.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:180331:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 9 -->
            <head>ACT, For a Publick Faſt.</head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Edinburgh, <date>the thirteenth Day of <hi>June,</hi> 1690. Years.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">O</seg>UR Soveraign Lord and Lady, The King and Queens Majeſties, and the Eſtates of Parliament, Taking to Their Conſideration, the preſent Conditi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the Kingdom of <hi>Ireland,</hi> and the great Dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers Threatning this Kingdom from thence; And that His Majeſty has Adventured to go thither in Perſon, for Reducing that Kingdom to its due Obedience, and thereby to Secure Our Religion and Peace; And it being the Indiſpenſible Duty <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> all the Leidges, as good Proteſtants, and Dutiful Subjects, in this <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ime of Common-danger, Seriouſly to Call upon Almighty God; and <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>arneſtly to Implore his Bleſſing upon this His Majeſties Undertaking, <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>r the Intereſt of the Proteſtant Religion, and the Safety of His King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms: Therefore, Their Majeſties, with Advice and Conſent of the <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ids Eſtates, Do Ordain and Appoint, That a Publick and Solemn Faſt <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd Humiliation, be Keeped and Obſerved throughout this Kingdom, by <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>l the Subjects, in a Devout and Decent Manner, to Pray to Almighty <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>od, for the Pardon of our Sins, and that he would be Graciouſly Pleaſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>d to Protect His Majeſty's Perſon, and to Bleſs His Arms with Succeſs: <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd that the ſaid Faſt be upon the Days following, <hi>viz.</hi> For the Shires on <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>his ſide of the River of <hi>Tay,</hi> upon <hi>Tueſday</hi> the Twenty fourth of <hi>June</hi> Inſtant; <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd for the Shires be-north <hi>Tay,</hi> upon the <hi>Tueſday</hi> thereafter, being the <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>rſt of <hi>July</hi> next; and Ordains the Miniſters to Intimat from their Pul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>its, the Obſervation of the ſaid Faſt, upon the Lords-day immediatly <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>receeding the ſaids reſpective Days, that the people may meet in the Churches, or other places where they ordinarly attend Divine Service, <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o hear Sermon, and joyn together in performing the Duties proper for <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ch a Solemnity. And Appoints this Act to be Printed, and publickly Proclaimed by Heraulds, Macers, or Purſevants, at the Mercat-Croſs of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and Printed Copies thereof to be diſpatched to the Sheriff-Clerks of the reſpective Shires, that they may ſend the ſame to the ſeveral Miniſters in the Shire, to Intimat the ſaid Faſt in manner foreſaid. Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracted forth of the Records of Parliament, by me</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>Th. Burnet,</hi> Cls. Reg.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>EDINB<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>RGH,</hi> Printed by the Heir of <hi>Andrew Anderſon,</hi> Printer to the King and Queens moſt Excellent Majeſties, <hi>Anno Dom.</hi> 1690.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
